<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>   
    <title>ThalBlog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://alexthaler.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://alexthaler.github.io</link>
    <description>Code, ideas and anything else that pops into my head.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 22:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>The mighty Wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Map Revalation</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/awesome_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 22:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/awesome_map/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I read a post on reddit that reminded me of why I spend so much time on that site.  It all started out with a post titled &quot;Worlds Population&quot; and linked to the followig image.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sJotonD.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;initial awesome map&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at this, it seriously blew my mind.  However I didn&apos;t have the reaction that a few on the comments did when they pointed out that the amount of land within that circle is actually much larger than displayed.  Looking further throught the comments I found this was definitely true and, of course, a relevant XKCD.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started when someone posted this image of the actual size of Africa that obviously conflicted with the posted images scale. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/uGTm3Wv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;zomg africa map&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with an awesomely relevant West Wing clip (I&apos;ve always had this on my to watch list but it&apos;s now right at the top and on netflix!) that&apos;s definitely worth the 4 min watch.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/n8zBC2dvERM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally culiminating in a great revised map created by another redditor showing, in fact, how much larger the area is.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/N7yPa7z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;super cool map&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please forgive the basically reposting of a reddit post, I know it happens often enough already.  However this seriously blew my mind so much I really wanted to at least save it so I could reference it later.  I always knew of the other maps you could reference but never understood how big a difference they actually presented.`

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/woahdude/comments/1dqw88/worlds_population_pic/&quot;&gt;Source Reddit Thread&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/977/&quot;&gt;Relevant XKCD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horae</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/horae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 20:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/horae/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanted to make a quick post about the new site I just finished up recently called Horae (Hoe-rai).  This site is basically just a wrapper for the Metra rail-time tracker on their site.  I built it out partially because their UI wasn&apos;t ideal and also to try and make something super simple so everyone could use it.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is &lt;a href=&quot;http://horae.herokuapp.com&quot;&gt;Horae&lt;/a&gt;.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s mobile optimized so you can easily check the train status at the station or quickly bring up the upcoming trains as you&apos;re walking there.  I know the design leaves something to be desired but give me a break I&apos;m just getting into this whole HTML/CSS thing :).  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate just wanted to make a quick post about it.  I might expand this later to go more in depth into the code but that&apos;ll have to wait for another night.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source is also up on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com/alexthaler/Horae&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlexThaler.com</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/new_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/new_website/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After many years I have finally taken the time to setup a real website that represents me.  It doesn&apos;t do anything and as such isn&apos;t very interesting.  However after looking around at the curtain style scrolling sites I&apos;d seen everywhere, the real inspriration came from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buildwindows.com/&quot;&gt;Microsoft build conference website&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/msft-build-screenie.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of the build page incase it is removed&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going off of this I tried to really take a shot at doing some interesting UI work (at least to me), as I haven&apos;t done real HTML UI work since… well ever really.  I also wanted to take this as an oppourtunity to try and learn some more CSS and specifically SASS.  Sass is seriously now my best friend, I used to hate doing css but sass I can grasp for some reason, the syntax of css I guess was just bugging me.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate after working on it for quite a bit this is now the new website and the first thing that uses a browser that doesn&apos;t use javascript heavily that I&apos;ve worked on it a long time.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexthaler.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/site-screenie.png&quot; alt=&quot;it&apos;s sooo pretty!&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think, obviously the content of the site itself is still being hashed out but the site is functional and looks rather good I must say.   

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So take a look and let me know what you think.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexthaler.com&quot;&gt;alexthaler.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive Sunday</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/grill_clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/grill_clean/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we had a burst of warmth here in Chicago recently I figured I&apos;d clean up my grill to get ready for summer.  Earlier in the winter I had a sizeable grease fire take place and had to douce it with half a pound of flour, leaving it in this state.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dirtygrill.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;dirty grill&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now after a good cleaning it looks much less like there was a snow explosion.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cleangrill.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;clean grill&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Automation</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/from_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/from_automation/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a test post to ensure that my autodeploy script is working.  I&apos;ll be writing up a full description of how it works very soon.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another modification, yay pancake bunny of awesomeness.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_PdnZ8gzHzOw/RtPSE1XxIAI/AAAAAAAAAZ4/iJvmpB_VLdo/s400/bunny_pancake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pancake bunny&quot;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello (new) World</title>
      <link>http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexthaler.github.io/articles/hello_world/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can probably tell the blog has undergone a major update and upgrade.  I&apos;m still working on the themeing and UI so expect more updates to come.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog is now being generated using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jnordberg.github.com/wintersmith/&quot;&gt;wintersmith&lt;/a&gt; which so far has been awesome (thanks jnordberg).  The change was partially because of my issues with Octopress and syncing across multiple repos.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working on some tools to aid in publishing a blog with winterpress which I will probably post later.  Until then please bare with me and the odd themeing.  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Now with 100% new theme.  Custom changes are still coming.

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>